Julian Franklin

Lompoc, CA

Phone: (732) 688-2211 | Email: <u>i.franks725@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/julian-franklin/ | GitHub: https://github.com/jfranklin12

Portfolio: https://jfranklin12.github.io/Portfolio-jfranklin/

Summary

Mission-oriented, organized, and solutions-driven full stack web developer with a web development certificate from Georgia Institute of Technology. Experience in education utilizing interpersonal skills to collaborate in a team environment, communicate effectively and efficiently manage a team and classroom. Distinct ability to design, build, and maintain websites from ideas to reality. Exceeds expectations by working in agile environments driven by collaboration, efficiency and determination.

Technical Skills

Git, Heroku, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, API Integration, MVC Structures, Mobile First and Responsive Design, Test-Driven Development, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Relational Mapping, SQL Server, MongoDB, Sequelize, Node.js, Apollo, MERN

Projects

DevBids

https://github.com/jfranklin12/devbids-contractor-Gp4 | https://devbids-gp4.herokuapp.com/ Platform designed to allow contractors to hire web developers through bidding.

- Created MongoDB through GraphQL and Mongoose
- Integrated database into React for website functionality

360 Degrees

https://github.com/jfranklin12/360-Degrees | https://threesixtydegrees.herokuapp.com/Blog for reviewing college degrees, preparing others for future life decisions.

- Integrated Materialize including parallax and autocomplete functionality
- Designed website style, HandleBars pages, and forms including mobile responsiveness
- Worked on server, MySQL, and sequelize database

Touch Grass

https://github.com/jfranklin12/touch-grass-app-national-park-finder | https://ashley1thompson.github.io/touch-grass-app-national-park-finder/ National Park Finder with interactive user technology

- Integrated National Park API for user search
- Created user search functionality

Experience

Fulton County Schools, Atlanta, GA

Team Lead August 2019 - May 2022

- Led the development and education of 151 students in 7 classrooms credited toward ranking 30th of 2365 elementary schools in Georgia 2021.
- Conducted assessment analysis used to execute academic plans students' academic growth higher than 96% of schools in Georgia.
- Coordinated and communicated schedule impacts.
- Proposed corrective solutions to mitigate risk.

Educator

August 2016 - May 2022

- Expedited progress in a fast-paced environment, working complex issues to meet deadlines.
- Planned and provided for instruction based on government given standards to facilitate and inspire performance mastery.
- Prepared and presented weekly reports based on growth and achievement to all levels of Management.
- Developed, managed, and analyzed a Master schedule, monitoring progress and identifying performance issues in a timely manner.
- Integrated multiple projects simultaneously by applying organizational, planning, management, problem solving & execution skills successfully.
- Supported and participated in communication with parents, administrators, and teachers to formulate new strategies for current and future education goals.
- Used Microsoft Office Suite applications to collaborate, communicate, manage, present, organize, schedule, and coordinate daily tasks, meetings, and milestone events.
- Diplomatically interacted with fellow teachers, administrators, school personal, and district employees to grow professionally, plan events, and complete daily tasks.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

June 2022 - September 2022

A 12 week intensive program focused on gaining skills in full stack web development including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and databases.

Early Childhood Education: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

August 2010 - May 2015

BSE in Early Childhood Education with English Speakers of Other Languages endorsement. Completed Reading Endorsement in 2022.